Finding Aid for the J. Warren Perry Correspondence and Autograph Collection, 1840-1995
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
J. Warren Perry Correspondence and Autograph Collection, 1840-1995
Mus. Arc. 3.3
Perry, J. Warren
1 box (83 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
83 items, including letters to Dr. Perry, autographed programs, and autographed cards.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. J. Warren Perry, 2004.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Dr. J. Warren Perry was born in Richmond, Indiana in 1921. He earned his B.A. at DePauw University in 1944, his Master's at Northwestern University in 1952, and his Ph.D. at Northwestern in 1955. Dr. Perry has been on the faculties at the University of Illinois at Chicago, Northwestern Medical School, and the University of Chicago. He was also employed as deputy assistant commissioner for research and training in the Vocational Rehabilitation Administration at the Department of Health, Education and Welfare in Washington, D.C. Dr. Perry is the founder of the School of Health Related Professions (now the School of Public Health and Health Professions) at the University at Buffalo, The State University of New York. He served as dean of the school from its founding in 1967 until 1977.
Dr. Perry has devoted much of his life to supporting the arts. Before moving to Buffalo he was one of the founders of the Lyric Opera Company in Chicago. Since arriving in Buffalo Dr. Perry has served as chairman or board member for several local organizations, including the Buffalo Philharmonic, Community Music School, Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural National Historic Site, Artpark, and Friends of the Center for the Arts. The numerous awards granted to honor Dr. Perry's contributions to the community include the Buffalo Arts Councils' Supporter of the Arts award, the Buffalo Distinguished Citizen Award, and national Outstanding Philanthropist Award.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains 83 items, including signed correspondence, autographed cards, programs, and music, and musical inscriptions. The correspondents and signatees are chiefly musicians and dancers. Included among them are Aaron Copland, Anna Moffo, Artur Rubinstein, Artur Rodzinski, Walter Damrosch, Maria Tallchief, Renata Tebaldi, Fritz Reiner, and Maria Callas.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series:
I. Correspondence and autographs
II. Autographs and inscriptions, 9 x 14 cm. or smaller
III. Autographs and correspondence in framed items
Container List
- Correspondence and autographs, 1940-1984, I.; Item 1-57
  Alphabetically arranged by author and then chronologically.
  - Ardoin, John Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, July 17, no year, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Baldwin, Dalton Correspondence to J. Warren Perry April 18, 1984, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Bampton, Rose Autographed program, University of Alabama October 29, 1951, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Bing, Rudolf, 1902-1997 General correspondence May 21, 1955, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Björling, Jussi, 1911-1960 Autographed program, Miami University March 21, 1950, 1 folded leaf (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Busch, Fritz, 1890-1951 Autographed program, Cincinnati Musical [May] Festival May 1950, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 6)
    Also autographed by Sullivan, Brian, 1919-1969
  - Cassidy, Claudia Correspondence to J. Warren Perry March 12, 1957, 1 typescript leaf, on Chicago Tribune letterhead (Box 1, Item 7)
  - Cleva, Fausto Autographed program, Cincinnati Summer Opera July 4, 1948, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 8)
    Also autographed by: Engelman, Wilfred; Jagel, Frederick; Moscona, Nicola; Pinza, Ezio
  - Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry (thank you note) February 12, 1950, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 9)
  - De Sabata, Victor, 1892-1967 1 leaf of King Edward Hotel, Toronto stationary, with autograph undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Elias, Rosalind Correspondence to J. Warren Perry March 16, 1982, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Fiedler, Arthur, 1894-1979 undated, 1 printed card, conductor at 4:30, with autograph (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 undated, 1 leaf of stationary from the Blackstone, Chicago, with autograph (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Ganz, Rudolf, 1877-1972 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry June 20, 1963, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Gardiner, Gladys Correspondence to unknown correspondent, possibly a joke March 25, 1964, 1 ms. leaf (Photocopy) (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Ghiringhelli, Antonio Correspondence to Charles D. Perry March 8, 1956, 1 typescript leaf, on Teatro alla Scala letterhead (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Harshaw, Margaret Autographed program page, Lohengrin, Cincinnati Summer Opera July 31, 1948, With cast list (1 leaf) (Box 1, Item 17)
    Also autographed by: Breisach, Paul; Jagel, Frederick; Varnay, Astrid
  - Harshaw, Margaret Autographed program page for Aida undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 18)
    Also autographed by: Baum, Kurt, 1900-1989; Moscona, Nicola; Pilotto, Angelo; Roman, Stella
  - Higgins, May Correspondence to J. Warren Perry May 5, [1962], 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 19)
    Refers to letter from Eva Turner (Item 55)
  - Higgins, May Correspondence to J. Warren Perry (Christmas card) undated, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 20)
    Refers to postcard from Renata Tebaldi (Item 49)
  - Hines, Jerome, 1921-2003 Autographed cast list for Cincinnati Summer Opera performance of Faust July 12, 1951, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 21)
    Also autographed by: Guarerra, Frank, 1923-; Quartatraro, Florence
  - Kelly, Lawrence Correspondence to J. Warren Perry October 30, 1957, 1 typescript leaf, on Dallas Civic Opera letterhead (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1916-1999 Autographed inscription to J. Warren Perry January 1948, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Moffo, Anna 1 printed wedding announcement for wedding of Anna Moffo to Mario Lanfranchi, Milan, Italy December 28, 1957, 1 card, with envelope addressed to J. Warren Perry (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from Belfast April 26, 1958, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from London May 19, 1958, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from Milan June 3, 1958, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from Milan June 14, 1958, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from Trieste July 30, 1958, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, from Chicago November 13, 1958, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry May 12, 1959, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope, separate sleeve (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Moffo, Anna Correspondence to J. Warren Perry, postcard from Palermo undated, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Page, Ruth, 1899-1991 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry June 25, 1958, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Page, Ruth, 1899-1991 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry July 14, 1959, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Peters, Roberta, 1930- Autographed cast list for Cincinnati Summer Opera performance of Rigoletto June 27, 1951, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 35)
    Also autographed by: Valdengo, Giuseppe, 1914-2007
  - Ponselle, Rosa, 1897-1981 Correspondence to Charles D. Perry, April 17, 1956, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Raisa, Rosa, 1893-1963 Correspondence to May Higgins May 26, 1961, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Raisa, Rosa, 1893-1963 Correspondence to May Higgins March 2, 1963, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Raisa, Rosa, 1893-1963 Autographed page of music from the score of Aida undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry June 17, 1958, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958 1945?, 1 leaf of Chicago Symphony Orchestra stationary, with autograph (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Rubinstein, Artur, 1887-1982 April 14, 1947, 1 leaf with autographed inscription to J. Warren Perry, April 14, 1947 (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Rubinstein, Artur, 1887-1982 Note to J. Warren Perry March 18, 1951, 1 leaf of Radisson Hotel, Minneapolis stationary, with autographed inscription to J. Warren Perry (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Sayaõ, Bidu Autographed program, Taft Auditorium, Cincinnati November 12, 1948, 1 program (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Shaw, Robert, 1916-1999 Autographed program, Miami University February 28, 1951, 1 program (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Stern, Isaac, 1920-2001 Autographed program, Miami University January 16, 1950, 1 program (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Swarthout, Gladys, 1904-1969 Autographed cast list for Cincinnati Summer Opera performance of Carmen July 23, 1950, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Tallchief, Maria Correspondence to J. Warren Perry June 17, 1959, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Tebaldi, Renata Correspondence to May Higgins, postcard, from Madrid December 12, 1974, 1 postcard (Box 1, Item 49)
  - Tebaldi, Renata Correspondence to J. Warren Perry February 25, 1994, 1 typescript leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 50)
  - Thebom, Blanche Autographed program, Miami University October 3, 1950, 1 program (Box 1, Item 51)
  - Thebom, Blanche Autographed cast list for Cincinnati Summer Opera performance of Carmen July 18, 1951, 1 program (Box 1, Item 52)
    Also autographed by: Sullivan, Brian
  - Tucker, Richard, 1913-1975 Autographed title page from libretto for Un ballo in maschera undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Item 53)
    Also autographed by: Roman, Stella; Valentino, Frank
  - Turner, Eva, Dame, 1892-1990 Correspondence to May Higgins May 23, 1961, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 54)
  - Turner, Eva, Dame, 1892-1990 Correspondence to May Higgins March 11, 1962, 1 typescript leaf (Box 1, Item 55)
  - Wildermann, William, 1919-2004 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry Jan. 31, 1963, 1 ms. leaf, with envelope (Box 1, Item 56)
  - Wildermann, William, 1919-2004 Correspondence to J. Warren Perry February 7, 1963, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 57)
- Autographs and inscriptions, 9 x 14 cm. or smaller, circa 1947-1952, II.; Item 58-83
  Alphabetically arranged by author and then chronologically
  - Baccaloni, Salvatore, 1900-1969 1947, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 58)
  - Baum, Kurt, 1900-1989 Autographed cast list for Cincinnati Summer Opera performance of Pagliacci July 18, 1950, 1 program (Box 1, Item 59)
    Also autographed by: Guarrera, Frank, 1923-2007
  - Bing, Rudolf, 1902-1997 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 60)
  - Bori, Lucrezia, 1887-1960 October 6, 1947, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 61)
  - Crooks, Richard, 1900-1972 1949, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 62)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 63)
  - Eddy, Nelson, 1901-1967 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 64)
  - Elias, Rosalind undated, 1 ms. leaf (Box 1, Item 65)
  - Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961 March 1948, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 66)
  - Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987 1947, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 67)
  - Jessner, Irene undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 68)
  - Johnson, Edward, 1878-1959 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 69)
  - Kostelanetz, Andre, 1901-1980 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 70)
  - Lazzari, Virgilio, 1887-1953 1949, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 71)
  - Melton, James, 1904-1961 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 72)
  - Mitropoulos, Dimitri, 1896-1960 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 73)
  - Munsel, Patrice, 1925- undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 74)
  - Pinza, Ezio undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 75)
  - Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 76)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 77)
  - Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 78)
  - Vinay, Ramon undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 79)
  - Warren, Leonard, 1911-1960 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 80)
  - Unidentified undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 81)
  - Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962 February 1952, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 82)
    With musical quote
  - Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962 undated, 1 ms. card (Box 1, Item 83)
    With musical quote from opening of Gustav Mahler’s Symphony no. 2, C minor
- Autographs and correspondence in framed items, 1840-1995, III.; Item 84-
  Framed items awaiting inventory.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Musicians--Correspondence; Perry, J. Warren--Correspondence
Genres
Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
J. Warren Perry Collection of Photographs, ca. 1910-1971
Mus. Arc. 3.1
A collection of 2110 photographs, chiefly of opera singers and productions, with additional photographs of conductors, performers, ensembles, and concert halls.
J. Warren Perry Collection of Ballet Photographs, ca. 1910-1960
Mus. Arc. 3.2
A collection of 300 photographs of ballet dancers, choreographers, and productions.